automobilesreview.com 2019-05-17

# Privacy Policy

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally Identifiable Information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website and when do we collect it?**

Automobilesreview.com collects some personal data from its visitors, in order to provide them with the best service possible. We collect this information when you log into our site with your Facebook, Google+ or LinkedIn account.

The information that we collect includes users’ first and last name, email address, gender and language.

Automobilesreview.com uses Google Analytics, which gathers some personal data from the visitors of the website, in order to provide users with possibly the best service. The data provided are processed in an anonymous segregated way, and they do not allow the identification of the specific user.

We use this information only for statistical purposes, for measuring the activity and the traffic to our website. We also use the data to improve our website’s navigation.

We do not collect the information that users provide to us when filling out our contact form. By sending us a message via our contact form, you agree to receive a response from AutomobilesReview to the email address, which you have provided in the email section.

**How do we use your information?**

We do not use the email address that you provide us with via our contact form for profiling or marketing aims. On this email you will only receive an email from AutomobilesReview with a response to your question/query/comment, etc.

We do not use your email for profiling or marketing aims.

Automobilesreview.com uses Google Analytics, which collects some personal data from website’s visitors, in order to provide them with the best service possible. The information that is collected from you is primarily used to personalize and enhance your attendance on Automobilesreview.com, to provide you with better user experience and with content which best fits your interests, as well as occasionally alert you of site changes, which may be relevant to your use of the site.

**How do we protect your information?**

Automobilesreview.com has taken all necessary technical and ethical precautions to grant that personal information submitted on the website is stored securely and treated according to the parameters present in this Privacy Policy.

We only provide users with pictures, articles and information. We never ask for credit card numbers.

We do not use Malware Scanning.

Users’ personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and who are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

We implement a variety of security measures when a user enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of their personal information.

**Do we use 'cookies'?**

Yes, we use cookies on Automobilesreview.com. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings.

If you turn cookies off, some of the features that make your site experience more efficient may not function properly.

To learn more about how we use cookies, please, visit our Cookie Policy Page: <https://www.automobilesreview.com/cookies/>

**Cookies utilization**

Automobilesreview.com collects cookies from your computer, as part of our continuous effort to understand the preferences of our audience and, at the same time, be helpful to our advertisers by supplying them with information about the way the site is used.

Please note that:

  * Cookies do not bear personally identifying information and are used for statistical data
  * Cookies can be turned off on any computer, as long as the option is chosen among the browser options. However, by disabling cookies, you might not be able to access certain sections of Automobilesreview.com, which require them to function properly
  * Cookies may also be collected by Google AdSense when you click on advertisements. However, Automobilesreview.com has no involvement in this process. You may learn more about how AdSense uses cookies on the following page: <https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/7549925?hl=en>

Users have the opportunity to change the settings of the way Google uses their data to show ads to them (read more on the following page: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/) )

We use different types of cookies for different purposes: (i) "required cookies" are necessary for our website to work properly, (ii) "performance cookies" allow us to analyze how Visitors use our website so we can measure and improve the performance of our website, (iii) "functional cookies" allow us to remember choices you may have made on our website, and (iv) "advertising cookies" are used to present ads that are relevant to your interests.

**We use cookies to:**

  * Understand and save user's preferences for future visits.
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf.

**Third-party disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information.

**Use of information collected from you about other individuals**

Automobilesreview.com contains sections where you may enter information about other individuals. We use this information only for the purposes, which it was submitted. I.e., if you completed a form to recommend our website to a friend, they will only receive your recommendation to visit our site.

**Message boards and other visitor-generated content**

Automobilesreview.com gives its visitors the opportunity to publish content in certain sections, such as message boards. This content is publicly available and subject to the site’s policy listed in the ‘User Content’ part of the ‘Terms and Conditions’ section, which is available here. (<https://www.automobilesreview.com/terms-conditions/>).

As a comment plug-in, we use Disqus. You may learn more about Disqus Privacy Policy and Terms of Service on the following page: <https://help.disqus.com/customer/en/portal/topics/215159-terms-and-policies>

When the user’s comment is approved and published on our website, the only visible user data is the name/username of the person who has written the comment. Their email address will not be published, and will not be used for any other purpose, except for giving the right to comment.

**Third-party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Google**

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. Read more on the following page: <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/>

**We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.**

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.

**We have implemented the following:**

We, along with third-party vendors such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

**Opting out:**

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require any person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting Personally Identifiable Information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared. - See more at: <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/>

**According to CalOPPA, we agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously.

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum, on the first significant page after entering our website. Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy' and can easily be found on the page specified above.

You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes on our Privacy Policy Page You can change your personal information by emailing us

**How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?**

We honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?**

It's also important to note that we allow third-party behavioral tracking. (Google Analytics)

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States' consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.

**Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

**In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**

We will notify you via email within 7 business days

We may revise or update our Terms and Conditions page or our Privacy Policy page at any time. You will be bound by any such revisions and should, therefore, periodically visit this page to remain updated on our current Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, you can contact us at any time via our contact page: <https://www.automobilesreview.com/contact-us/>
